<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathew Cohle</title>
    <link>https://mathewcohle.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mathew Cohle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 20:50:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mathewcohle.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing No Quid Pro Quo</title>
      <link>https://mathewcohle.github.io/2020/01/doing-no-quid-pro-quo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 20:50:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mathewcohle.github.io/2020/01/doing-no-quid-pro-quo/</guid>
      <description>If you are asked to do something, do it unconditionally &amp;ndash; without expecting anything in return. No more scratching the back only if you scratch mine.
Doing the favor conditionally builds an expectation which either ends with the things going as expected or being disappointment if the promise is not fulfilled. Thus, it is equivalent of the trade with small upside but rather large downside. Lot of sadness around the world could disappear with better expectation management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things Tend To Change</title>
      <link>https://mathewcohle.github.io/2020/01/things-tend-to-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 19:01:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mathewcohle.github.io/2020/01/things-tend-to-change/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I read the book The Art of Living: Vipassana Meditation. There is chapter called The Two Rings1 describing a story which goes something like this:
 Two brothers inherit the property after the death of father. Later on, they get into a fight and decide to split all the property equally &amp;ndash; except packet with two rings, one expensive and the other just regular silver ring. The older brother argues his way to take the expensive one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Am Doing Now</title>
      <link>https://mathewcohle.github.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:04:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mathewcohle.github.io/now/</guid>
      <description>Distraction Free Life I remember the exact moment when I observed my mind being absolutely incapable to focus, not able to remember anything &amp;ndash; rather disturbing experience.
 disabled phone notification started to use phone in Greyscale mode most of the time removed messenger application from home screen, checking new messages irregularly stopped using social network stopped reading news on daily basis  Learning Rust, Full Time Without Excuses Finally, things get serious.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>